

# **Brian D. Harris**

**Customer Experience Researcher and Designer** 801-414-8652 | uxbrianharris@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/brian-harris-research

## Summary

**Expert mixed-methods researcher and UX specialist.** Vast repertoire of qualitative and quantitative methodologies and techniques. High-productivity, low-maintenance problem-solver for complex challenges. Creative idea generator with strategic insight. Excellent communicator, coordinating proactively and reporting clearly. Fluent in Spanish. Motivated by client trust and relentlessly pursuing user satisfaction. Strong record of learning new skills. Able to offer cross-disciplinary assistance in research, design, product development, and analytics.

#### **Skills**

- Survey design, segmentation
- Site-intercepts
- Interviews and focus groups
- Journey mapping
- Design thinking
- Diary studies and ethnography
- Discrete choice and conjoint
- Jobs-to-Be-Done methods

- Iterative product development
- Wireframes and prototypes
- Usability testing
- Figma, Adobe XD
- SPSS, Stata, Excel
- Qualtrics, UserTesting, dScout
- Visual data presentation
- Fluent in Spanish

## **Professional Experience**

## Customer Insights Manager | Purple Innovations | Oct 2020-present

Helped build a new Customer Insights team for a young and fast-growing brand. Led the UX Research team for four months prior to new Director of Insights. Consulted with directors and staff within CMO's organization (eCommerce, Merchandising, Retail, Wholesale, Creative and Brand) to improve product offerings, online web experience, physical retail spaces, brand identity, and post-purchase experience. Managed research vendor relationships to produce critical insights for the entire business. Hired, managed, and mentored a new employee.

- Established baseline industry knowledge for the company through hundreds of consumer interviews, including insights about Purple and key competitors.
- Stood up listening posts and intercepts throughout the eComm user journey.
- Improved product margins and increased revenue through a discrete choice model study to evaluate promotional offer combinations.
- Improved the brand's "premium feel" as well as the customer experience of information gathering through mixed methods benchmarking and iterative testing of key user flows.
- Improved new adjustable base by designing and testing physical remote control user interfaces and product-related apps.
- Tested top-performing advertisements and defined drivers of success for advertising to certain audience segments. Helped establish ongoing ad testing with a vendor specializing in biometrics and creative.
- Established and managed an ongoing secret shopper program for Wholesale.

#### Senior Researcher | Boncom | Aug 2019-Aug 2020

Director of research for entire ad agency. Led simultaneous high-profile projects with minimal supervision.

- Managed internal and external data collection to steer rebranding a
  professional musical performance organization, including new logos, taglines,
  organizational values, purpose statements, and brand promises.
- Informed creative strategy for Utah Department of Health initiatives:
  - o *Live On*, suicide prevention campaign
  - o Stop the Opidemic, substance abuse and mental health resources
  - o Zero Fatalities, safe driving initiative
- Researched expected offerings, naming, logos, style and tone for www.skylight.org. Organized and launched beta tests with recurring panel of app users. Informed web experience design.
- Supervised segmentation and journey mapping research for an online university to understand its students, motivations for enrolling, current experiences, and marketing opportunities.
- Directed research to guide management transfer of historic sites. Produced clear guiding principles for the Historic Sites Division and creative recommendations for improved visitor experience.





linkedin.com/in/ brian-harris-research

801.414.8652

#### Study Lead and Researcher | LDS Church Research Division | Jan 2013-Aug 2019

Senior researcher with responsibilities in study planning, vendor management, panel management, survey administration, project management, and delegation to junior colleagues. Frequent internal client consultation.

- Repaired strained interdepartmental relationships while coordinating multiphase international test pilot for new youth activity program. On-time global implementation lauded by executives.
- Directed international pilot research for new seminary curriculum to guide development. Evaluated implementation fidelity and objectives and offered human-centered recommendations.
- Strengthened interfaith partnerships by leading an international study among Muslim-born converts to explore messaging for new publication for use in humanitarian efforts in Muslim-majority countries, highlighting shared values.
- Provided qualitative and quantitative feedback regarding missionary mobile device training. Piloted mobile device roll-out leading to fully operational global program with more effective proselyting and fewer behavior problems.
- Provided insights into convert retention by designing a longitudinal study to identify when and why individuals stop attending, with actionable suggestions.
- Administrated Qualtrics license for over 1,500 employees. Consulted across organization on survey design and methodology. Developed standard procedures for research division to oversee studies throughout organization.
- Conducted research internationally, including managing local research vendors and translators in Africa and Oceania, and personally conducting focus groups in Spanish throughout Latin America.

## Instructor | UC Irvine and Brigham Young University | 2010-2012

Taught seven upper-level university courses in probability, statistics, research methods, data analysis, and data presentation. Developed course curricula. Tutored individual students and led study group sessions.

## **Education**



uxbrianharris@gmail.com



801.414.8652



linkedin.com/in/ brian-harris-research

Brian Harris – Page 3

- UX/UI Bootcamp Certificate | University of Utah | 2021
   Learned UX design tools (Figma, Adobe XD) and coding in HTML and CSS. Able to support and fill designer roles.
- Master of Science (MS), Sociology | Brigham Young University | 2011 Emphasis on statistics and quantitative methods, qualitative methods, inequality, immigration, and digital communication.
- Progress toward PhD, Sociology | University of California, Irvine | 2011-2012
   Completed required coursework. Left program for full-time applied research career. Specialized in statistics, research methods, communication, immigration, and inequality.
- Bachelor of Science (BS), Sociology | Brigham Young University | 2009
   Emphasis on research design, statistics, and research methodology.

#### **Publications**

- Harris, B. D. and T. L. Goodsell. 2011. "Family Life and Marathon Running: Constraint, Cooperation, and Gender in a Leisure Activity." Journal of Leisure Research 43(1): 80-109.
- Harris, B. D., C. V. Morgan and B. G. Gibbs. 2013. "Evidence of Political Moderation over Time: Utah's Immigration Debate Online." New Media & Society 16(8): 1309-1331.
- T. L. Goodsell, **B. D. Harris**, and B. W. Bailey. 2013 "Family Status and Motivations to Run: A Qualitative Study of Marathon Runners." Leisure Sciences 35(4): 337-352.





801.414.8652

